<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on The Long Journey</title>
    <link>http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on The Long Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2015 Alessandro Baffa.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:37:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox Of Choice In Learning to Code</title>
      <link>http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/2016/05/16/the-paradox-of-choice-in-learning-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:37:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/2016/05/16/the-paradox-of-choice-in-learning-to-code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was talking with a guy some days ago and it went like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;he told me &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I really would like to start improving myself and I need a pet project..&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I said &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;great idea! But where do you want to improve?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;he said &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;..that&amp;rsquo;s the problem: I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what I want to use. There are so many things out there that I would like to learn &amp;hellip; and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me think about a book I read some time ago called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Paradox-Choice-Why-More-Less/dp/149151423X&#34;&gt;The Paradox of Choice: Why More Is Less&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (the author gave also an awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_the_paradox_of_choice?language=en&#34;&gt;TED Talk&lt;/a&gt; about it). Basically the book talks about the relationship between the huge amount of choices we have nowadays with our happiness and freedom. People tend to think that having more choices (e.g.: more jeans in the shop to choose from, more books in the library, more courses on a learning platform, etc..) means that we have more &lt;em&gt;freedom&lt;/em&gt;, you are free to choose the thing that is more appropriate for you. The more the things we can choose from, the more free we are.&lt;br /&gt;
The author debunks this myth showing that the fact to have so many different choices doesn&amp;rsquo;t lead people to &lt;em&gt;feel more free&lt;/em&gt;, but instead it leads them to a &lt;em&gt;paralysis&lt;/em&gt; (in their mental choice process) and to a constant feeling of regret: you buy a book and you soon regret to not have bought the other one in your wish list (&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;perhaps it was better&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;).&lt;br /&gt;
Constant dissatisfaction instead of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing is happening nowadays with technology and, more specifically, with programming. There are so many choices out there to choose from that people, like the guy I was talking to, don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;em&gt;where to start&lt;/em&gt;. Javascript? Well, good luck. AngularJS? Oh wait, which one? &lt;em&gt;Angular 2 is coming&lt;/em&gt;. Java 8? Wait wait, Java 9 is scheduled for next year. Machine Learning? No no, the next &lt;em&gt;big-thing-I-am-sure&lt;/em&gt; will be Server-less architecture. Go, Haskell, Scala, Kotlin, Rust &amp;hellip; and if you want to pick just one platform to learn you can choose among Coursera, HackerRank, TopCoder, EggHead, CodeAcademy, CodeSchool, Udemy, Udacity &amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;UNLIMITED-OPTIONS-AVAILABLE&lt;/strong&gt;! The consequence is that people don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start if they try to follow this entropy. &lt;br /&gt;
The bad news is that Software Engineering is a field that changes so rapidly that all these things listed above will change in a couple of years. Again. So, it&amp;rsquo;s time to stop your mental chaos. How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-choosing:71dc9aeb37beba07c4d0736dfed6da34&#34;&gt;Stop choosing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book provides a simple solution to this paralysis: stop choosing. Do not spend mental energy regretting your choice because &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; the other one could have been better. If the difference is not so relevant (in terms of price, time, etc..) stop feeling bad and start to fully enjoy what you already have. There will be always something absolutely better out there, but what you have is already good enough.&lt;br /&gt;
What does it mean for developers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-yourself-the-right-question:71dc9aeb37beba07c4d0736dfed6da34&#34;&gt;Ask yourself the right question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one way to face the increasing entropy: a solid knowledge of the basics of Software Engineering. Stop choosing the next programming language or technology to learn. The question you should ask yourself should not be &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;should I choose between X and Y?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, but instead it should be &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;What I want to become? A professional developer or a simple coder?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself how well do you know things like design patterns, software design, cohesion, coupling, data structures, algorithms&amp;hellip;are you able to have a discussion about these things with other technical people? Do you think to have enough knowledge to decide the good strategies to write clean and testable code?&lt;br /&gt;
If your answer is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; or you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, well you&amp;rsquo;ve narrowed your options. Do a step back, that&amp;rsquo;s where you have to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologies change every time. Having strong knowledge foundations is what makes the difference between a professional developer and a simple coder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surrounding yourself with the right people</title>
      <link>http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/2016/02/23/surrounding-yourself-with-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alebaffa.github.io/blog/2016/02/23/surrounding-yourself-with-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../../../img/cerini.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;passion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was 8 years old when I started playing guitar. It was not my choice, though, but my parents’ who forced me to start taking some lessons. I hated it at the beginning: hours of solfège, and I wasn’t even able to play the most stupid song. No chords, nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless I had some natural talent for music (I’m gifted with the so called musical ear. And so my brother and sister are - the Force is strong in my family), and maybe my parents knew that and that’s why they persisted so much with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passed and I learned chords and arpeggios. I actually became so good until the point where my teacher told me that I was his most successful student ever, and he didn’t have anything more to teach me. He suggested me to go to the conservatory, but it was too much of an engagement both for me and for my parents and so I quite taking lessons.
I remember I felt relieved. No more lessons, no more waste of my precious time (1 hour / week &amp;hellip;). I could spend that hour playing football with my friends. So I quit playing guitar in general.
I was 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t touch my guitar for about 7 years, until a summer when I made a new friend. He was (he still is) an extraordinary guitarist, and he was able to reproduce all the songs he knew just listening to them for few minutes. He was always the coolest guy of the party. And he was/is also an extremely nice and funny guy. I loved the way he played his guitar, and his passion was so contagious that he made me willing to take mine and start playing again. During those few weeks my passion came back with all its strength. I started to learn new chords, find new ones and I soon realized that I was not so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My passion was driving me to a new level of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt; and I found some things to be easier than I thought years before. &lt;strong&gt;My friend’s passion has triggered mine&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve been playing guitar no-stop for years since then, and I improved so much. I own two guitars now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also love photography. I started to take photos when I first came here in south of France from Italy. The scenery was beautiful and so I thought to buy my first DSLR (a Nikon D70s). When I started using it I was very bad, I wasn’t even able to take a good photo in normal conditions and all those gears were difficult to manage. After some months with no improvements I gave up. I didn’t use my Nikon for about a year until I registered to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://kelbyone.com/&#34;&gt;online course&lt;/a&gt; where I discovered the post-processing. I was hooked. I discovered a new entire world of possibilities and so I started to improve my photos in order to apply all those cools things I was looking on the web. Then I tried &lt;a href=&#34;http://strobist.blogspot.fr/2011/01/introducing-strobist-lighting-in-layers.html&#34;&gt;another one&lt;/a&gt;, and in one year I hugely improved my skills and now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alebaffa/&#34;&gt;I’m not so bad&lt;/a&gt;. Again, something that has brought my passion back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrounding yourself with passion and optimism is one of the best things you can do to improve yourself and your environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the reason why I started to go to conferences: once back home you’re so full of enthusiasm that you restart whatever you do with a new energy.
It’s the reason why I started to co-organize a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/French-Riviera-Software-Craftsmanship-Community/&#34;&gt;local Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.
It’s also the reason why I like being a developer advocate, because I meet and work with so many passionate people who trigger my passion and pro-activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being surrounded by passionate people can speed up your learning process by giving you that amount of motivation that you sometime may lose on your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>